战争结束了 凛冬已至
The war is over. Winter has come.
战争尚未结束
The war is not over.
真正的敌人不会等到风暴结束才进攻
The true enemy won't wait out the storm.
北境之王！北境之王！
The King in the North! The King in the North!
我们的叔叔攸伦 在消失很久后回来了
Our uncle Euron returned home after a long absence.
他谋杀了我们的父亲 从雅拉手中夺走了盐王座
He murdered our father, and took the Salt Throne from Yara.
如果我们还留在那 也一样会死在他手里
He would have murdered us if we'd stayed.
给我造出千万条船 我会给你们整个世界
Build me a thousand ships, and I will give you this world.
风暴将至
There's a storm coming.
今晚你们需要庇护
You'll be wanting a roof tonight.
我没什么钱 但我藏了一点银鹿
I don't have much, but I have hidden a bit of silver
以防强盗
from the bandits.
你都干了些什么？！
What did you do?!
冬天到了 他们都会死
They'll both be dead come winter.
北境已经起了冷风
Cold winds are rising in the North.
我们需要好帮手
We need good men to help us.
比起你曾经伤害过的人 你还能帮助更多人 克里冈
You can still help a lot more than you've harmed, Clegane.
对你来说这绝对不晚
It's not too late for you.
派我去旧镇
Send me to Oldtown.
我会成为新的学士
I'm to be the new maester.
学城有世上最伟大的图书馆
The Citadel has the world's greatest library.
我将潜心学习那些能帮到我们的知识 当……
I'll learn about things that all help when...
当他们来临的时候
when they come.
跟我跑
Let go of me!
你确定你准备好了吗
Are you sure you're ready for this?
我现在是三眼乌鸦了 必须准备好
I'm the three-eyed raven. I have to be ready for this.
戴佛斯爵士 你知道这张桌子是谁雕刻喷涂的吗？
Do you know who had this table carved and painted, Ser Davos?
伊耿·坦格利安
Aegon Targaryen.
伊耿曾住在这 坦格利安家族修建了这座城堡
Aegon used to live here, and the Targaryens built this castle.
没错
Aye. So they did.
我希望咱俩一起回家 但我们的家早被人夺走了
I want us both to go home. But they took it from us.
我们该如何回家啊？
How do we go home?
你现在已身处权力的游戏之中
You're in the great game now,
而权力的游戏凶险异常 你害怕了吗？
and the great game's terrifying. Are you afraid?
我是艾莉亚·史塔克 你要知道这一点
My name is Arya Stark. I want you to know that.
瓦德·佛雷
孪河城侯爵
你们都很疑惑 我为什么让你们聚在这里
You're wondering why I brought you all here.
毕竟 我们才刚刚举行了一次盛宴
After all, we just had a feast.
上一次老家伙
Since when does old Walder
在两周之内举行两场宴会是什么时候的事了？
give us two feasts in a single fortnight?
如果不能和家族一起庆祝
Well, it's no good being Lord of the Riverlands
还算什么河间地之主啊
if you can't celebrate with your family.
对吧！
That's what I say!
没错！
Yes!
我召集了每一个姓佛雷的混蛋东西
I've gathered every Frey who means a damn thing
来听我给你们讲讲家族的计划
so I can tell you my plans for this great house
毕竟凛冬已至
now that winter has come.
但是首先 让我们举杯！
But first, a toast!
再也没有多恩马尿！
No more of that Dornish horse piss!
这是青亭岛最好的金色葡萄酒！
This is the finest Arbor gold!
美酒配英雄！
Proper wine for proper heroes!
风雨同舟！
Stand together!
你别喝
Not you.
我不想把美酒浪费在一个蠢女人身上
I'm not wasting good wine on a damn woman.
也许我不是最讨人喜欢的人
Maybe I'm not the most pleasant man.
这点我承认 但我为你们深感自豪
I'll admit it. But I'm proud of you lot.
你们是我的族人 为我倾囊相助的人
You're my family, the men who helped me
在血色婚礼上帮我剿灭史塔克家族
slaughter the Starks at the Red Wedding.
没错 没错
Yes, yes.
干杯吧
Cheer.
你们都是勇敢的人啊
Brave men, all of you.
把怀着孩子的女人活生生杀死
Butchered a woman pregnant with her babe.
把养育了五个孩子的母亲割了喉
Cut the throat of a mother of five.
就在你们家里
Slaughtered your guests after inviting them
把所有邀请来的客人屠戮殆尽
into your home.
但你们没有杀死所有姓史塔克的人
But you didn't slaughter every one of the Starks.
不 不 这是你们犯的错
No, no, that was your mistake.
你们该把他们全族歼灭 连根拔起
You should have ripped them all out, root and stem.
若一狼尚存
Leave one wolf alive
羊群便永不得安
and the sheep are never safe.
艾莉亚·史塔克
当人们问起你这里发生了什么……
When people ask you what happened here...
你就告诉他们北境永不遗忘
tell them the North remembers.
告诉他们 凛冬已至佛雷家
Tell them winter came for House Frey.
最专业冰火字幕
诚意奉献
专注GOT剧集
翻译 熊岛莱安娜
君临 King's Landing
翻译 叽拇啾
翻译 芹泽多摩熊
红堡
Red Keep
翻译 凯岩城的黑发狮子
翻译 Ashara_C
翻译 Taffy的北境雪诺
龙石岛Dragonstone
校对 临冬城的狮子 依依Eva
校对 北落师门 兮迩CeCe
孪河城The Twins
后期 依依Eva
监制 北落师门
临冬城
Winterfell
监制 临冬城的狮子
联合出品
史诗图书 | 冰火中文维基 | 黑城堡奇幻微刊
Epic Books         ASOIAF.huiji.wiki          Heichengbao
最专业的华语冰火资料站：        冰与火之歌中文维基
http://asoiaf.huiji.wiki
推广 baozhenyuawabi
绝境长城 the Wall
策划 衣柜军团
史诗图书
Epic Books
特别顾问 屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
旧镇Oldtown
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
衣柜字幕组
协力制作
史诗图书
Epic Books
ASOIAF.huiji.wiki
冰火中文维基
黑城堡
EPICASTLE
第一集
龙石岛
Dragonstone
布兰·史塔克
“忧郁的”艾迪
守夜人
你是野人？
You wildlings?
我是梅拉·黎德 霍兰·黎德之女
I'm Meera Reed, daughter of Howland Reed.
这是布兰登·史塔克
This is Brandon Stark,
梅拉·黎德
奈德·史塔克之子
son of Ned Stark.
我怎么知道你说的是真是假？
How do I know that's true?
你曾在先民拳峰
You were at the Fist of the First Men.
也曾在艰难屯
You were at Hardhome.
你亲眼目睹尸鬼大军
You've seen the Army of the Dead.
你还看见过夜王
You've seen the Night King.
他就要来找我们了
He's coming for us.
所有人都不例外
For all of us.
那好 来吧
Okay, come on.
让他们进来
Let's get them inside.
我下令让所有北境的学士去搜寻
I want every northern maester to scour their records
他们记录中任何关于龙晶的部分
for any mention of dragonglass.
龙晶能够杀死异鬼
Dragonglass kills white walkers.
这对我们来说比黄金更无价
It's more valuable to us now than gold.
我们需要找到龙晶 开采龙晶
We need to find it, we need to mine it,
琼恩·雪诺
北境之王
用龙晶来制造武器
we need to make weapons from it.
每一个年龄在十岁到六十岁之间的人
Everyone aged 10 to 60
都要每天练习长枪 尖矛和弓箭技艺
will drill daily with spears, pikes, bow and arrow.
这些在长夏出生的男孩 是时候学学怎么战斗了
It's about time we taught these boys of summer how to fight.
罗贝特·葛洛佛
深林堡伯爵
不能仅仅是男孩们
Not just the boys.
一半人作战
We can't defend the North
不足以保卫北境
if only half the population is fighting.
你想要我把长矛塞到我孙女手里？
You expect me to put a spear in my granddaughter's hand?
我可不打算在男人为我打仗的时候 自己在炉火旁边做针线活
I don't plan on knitting by the fire while men fight for me.
莱安娜·莫尔蒙
熊岛伯爵夫人
葛洛佛大人 或许我个头比较小 还是个姑娘
I might be small, Lord Glover, and I might be a girl,
但我身体里流淌着北境人的血液 与你分毫不差
but I am every bit as much a Northerner as you.
这话没错 夫人 没人质疑这点……
Indeed you are, my lady. No one has questioned...
要守卫北境 我可不需要由你批准
And I don't need your permission to defend the North.
戴佛斯·席渥斯
“洋葱骑士”
接下来 我们将会训练熊岛上的男女老少
We'll begin training every man, woman, boy, and girl on Bear Island.
遵命！
Aye!
在备战的同时
While we're preparing for attack,
我们得加固防线
we need to shore up our defenses.
珊莎·史塔克
当前阻挡着亡灵大军的只有长城
The only thing standing between us and the Army of the Dead is the Wall,
数百年来 长城并未得到妥善管理
and the Wall hasn't been properly manned in centuries.
我不是自由民之王
I'm not the king of the Free Folk.
但倘若我们想共同渡过这个严冬……
But if we're going to survive this winter together...
你是让我们去驻守那些堡垒？
You want us to man the castles for you?
托蒙德
野人
对
Aye.
上一次见到夜王 还是在艰难屯
Last time we saw the Night King was at Hardhome.
而离艰难屯最近的地方 是东海望
The closest castle to Hardhome is Eastwatch-by-the-Sea.
那我就去那儿
Then that's where I'll go.
似乎我们都成了守夜人
Looks like we're the Night's Watch now.
如果异鬼突破了长城
If they breach the Wall,
在它们南下之路上还有两个城堡
the first two castles in their path
最后壁炉城和卡霍城
are Last Hearth and Karhold.
可安柏家和卡史塔克家背叛了北境
The Umbers and the Karstarks betrayed the North.
约恩·罗伊斯
"青铜约恩"谷地领主
他们的城堡也应当被摧毁
Their castles should be torn down
片瓦不留
with not a stone left standing.
城堡可是无辜的
The castles committed no crimes.
更何况我们需要它们来应对接下来的战斗
And we need every fortress we have for the war to come.
那我们应当把这两座堡垒交给其他家族
We should give the Last Hearth and Karhold to new families,
作为回报 感谢他们效忠我们 共同对抗拉姆斯
loyal families who supported us against Ramsay.
没错！
Aye!
安柏家族和卡史塔克家族
The Umbers and the Karstarks
为史塔克家效力数百年
have fought beside the Starks for centuries.
一代代人誓约忠诚
They've kept faith for generation after generation.
可他们却背信弃义
And then they broke faith.
我不会仅仅因为部分人犯下的罪
I'm not going to strip these families of their ancestral homes
把这两个家族的后人赶出他们代代相传的古堡
because of the crimes of a few reckless sons.
难道背叛就不应该受罚？
So there's no punishment for treason
难道忠诚就不应该嘉奖？
and no reward for loyalty?
死亡正是背叛的惩罚
The punishment for treason is death.
小琼恩·安柏死在战场上
Smalljon Umber died on the field of battle.
霍拉德·卡史塔克死在战场上
Harald Karstark died on the field of battle.
他们是为拉姆斯战死的
They died fighting for Ramsay.
这些城堡应赏赐给效忠于你的家族
Give the castles to the families
他们可是为你而死
of the men who died fighting for you.
当我担任守夜人总司令时……
When I was Lord Commander of the Night's Watch...
我处决了背叛我的人
I executed men who betrayed me.
我处决了拒不听令的人
I executed men who refused to follow orders.
父亲常说
My father always said,
“处刑之人 应亲自动手”
"The man who passes the sentence should swing the sword,"
我试着去遵照父亲的教诲而活
and I have tried to live by those words.
但我不会因某人犯下了罪 就迁怒于他的后代
But I will not punish a son for his father's sins,
我也不会把这些家族的后人
and I will not take a family home away
从世代生活的城堡中赶走
from a family it has belonged to for centuries.
我已经做出了决定
That is my decision,
无需再议
and my decision is final.
奈德·安柏
Ned Umber.
亚丽·卡史塔克
Alys Karstark.
上百年来 我们的家族
For centuries, our families fought
一直并肩作战
side by side on the battlefield.
我要求你们以封臣的身份
I ask you to pledge your loyalty once again to House Stark,
再一次向史塔克家族效忠
to serve as our bannermen
无论何时 听从号令
and come to our aid whenever called upon.
起立
Stand.
之前的恩怨都一笔勾销
Yesterday's wars don't matter anymore.
北境要团结起来
The North needs to band together,
所有活着的北境人
all the living north.
奈德和亚丽 你们是否效忠我？
Will you stand beside me, Ned and Alys,
从一而终？
now and always?
从一而终！
Now and always!
你是我的妹妹 但如今我是北境之王
You are my sister, but I am king now.
看来要给你准备顶王冠啰？
Will you start wearing a crown?
你当着其他领主的面
When you question my decisions
质疑我的决定时 就是在拆我的台
in front of the other lords and ladies, you undermine me.
我现在都不能质疑你的决定了？
So I can't question your decisions anymore?
你当然可以 但……
Of course you can, but...
乔佛里从不准别人质疑他的权威
Joffrey never let anyone question his authority.
难道你认为他是个好国王？
You think he was a good king?
你认为我会像乔佛里一样？
Do you think I'm Joffrey?
你是我见过的人里最不像乔佛里的
You're as far from Joffrey as anyone I've ever met.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你擅长这个 你知道的
You're good at this, you know.
- 你是指什么方面？ - 领导众人
- At what? - At ruling.
不
No.
是这样的
You are.
的确如此
他们发自内心地尊敬你
They respect you, they really do,
可你得……
but you have to...
你笑什么？
Why are you laughing?
父亲常说什么来着？
What did father used to say?
“但是”前面的所有话都是胡扯
Everything before the word "but" is horse shit.
他从未对我说过这话
He never said that to me.
不 不 父亲不会在女儿面前吐脏话的
No. No, he never cursed in front of his girls.
那是因为他想要保护我们
Because he was trying to protect us.
他不想让我们见到真实世界的丑恶
He never wanted us to see how dirty the world really is,
但父亲始终没能保护我 你也是
but father couldn't protect me and neither can you.
别这么做了
Stop trying.
好 好 我不会再护着你了
All right, I'll stop trying to protect you
你也别再拆我台
and you stop trying to undermine me.
我才不是要拆你台！
I'm not trying to undermine you!
你得比父亲更聪明
You have to be smarter than father.
比罗柏更聪明
You need to be smarter than Robb.
我爱他们 想念他们 可他们确实犯了傻
I loved them, I miss them, but they made stupid mistakes,
还因此丢了性命
and they both lost their heads for it.
那我该怎么做才算是更聪明？
And how should I be smarter?
听你的话就行了？
By listening to you?
这么做真那么糟糕吗？
Would that be so terrible?
陛下 这是君临的来信
A raven from King's Landing, Your Grace.
“兰尼斯特家族的瑟曦一世
"Cersei of House Lannister, First of Her Name,
安达尔人与先民的女王
Queen of the Andals and the First Men,
七国统治者暨全境守护者……”
Protector of the Seven Kingdoms..."
她想怎样？
What does she want?
她要我们到君临去
Come to King's Landing.
向她求饶 否则就准备接受叛乱者的命运
Bend the knee or suffer the fate of all traitors.
你一直忧心于北边的敌人
You've been so consumed with the enemy to the north,
却忽略了南方的强敌
you've forgotten about the one to the south.
我之所以对夜王忧心忡忡 是因为我亲眼见到了他
I'm consumed with the Night King because I've seen him.
相信我 如果你也见到了他 不可能置之不顾
And believe me, you'd think of little else if you had, too.
我们和夜王之间毕竟还有道墙
We still have a wall between us and the Night King.
我们和瑟曦之间可什么都没有
There's nothing between us and Cersei.
我们和瑟曦之间相隔千里
There's a thousand miles between us and Cersei.
凛冬已至 兰尼斯特军队是南方之敌
Winter is here. The Lannisters are a southern army.
他们从未深入如此之北
They've never ranged this far north.
你是个军人 但我更了解她
You're the military man, but I know her.
如果你与瑟曦为敌 她会摧毁你 不达目的不罢休
If you're her enemy, she'll never stop until she's destroyed you.
但凡有人想阻挠她 她都会千方百计先杀了你
Everyone who's ever crossed her, She's found a way to murder.
听起来你好像很钦佩她
You almost sound as if you admire her.
我只是从她身上学到很多罢了
I learned a great deal from her.
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者” 御林铁卫队长
这是什么？
What is this?
我们等待了一辈子的一切
It's what we've been waiting for our whole lives.
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
铁王座上的女王
父亲教育我们的目的就在于此 不管他是否意识得到
It's what father trained us for, whether he knew it or not.
他知道的
He knew it.
他让我记住每一个该死的城市 小镇
Made me memorize every damn city, town,
河流 森林 还有山脉
lake, forest, and mountain.
现在都是我们的了 只要去拿过来就好
It's ours now. We just have to take it.
自从回家后 你一直沉默寡言
You've been quiet since you came home.
在生我的气么？
Are you angry with me?
不 我没有生气
No, not angry.
那就是在怕我咯？
Are you afraid of me?
我该怕吗？
Should I be?
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安已经有提利昂作为女王之手了
Daenerys Targaryen has chosen Tyrion to be her Hand.
而现在他们正渡过狭海而来
Right now, they're sailing across the Narrow Sea,
企图夺回她父亲的王座
hoping to take back her father's throne.
我们的弟弟
Our little brother,
你深爱的那个弟弟
the one you love so much,
被你放走的弟弟
the one you set free,
杀害了我们的父亲和长子的弟弟
the one who murdered our father and our first-born son,
如今他和我们的敌人并肩作战 还为他们出谋划策
now he stands beside our enemies and gives them counsel.
在船上逍遥快活
He's out there somewhere at the head of an armada.
他们准备在哪里登陆？
Where will they land?
龙石岛
Dragonstone.
那里有深水港口 能停放大型舰队
They have deep-water ports for the ships.
史坦尼斯留下了一座空城
Stannis left the castle unoccupied,
而且那里还是她出生的地方
and that's where she was born.
这是东面之敌
Enemies to the east.
而南面之敌……
Enemies to the south...
是艾拉莉亚·沙德还有她养的那群婊子们
Ellaria Sand and her brood of bitches.
西面之敌……
Enemies to the west...
是奥莲娜这个老婊子
Olenna, the old cunt.
还是个叛徒
Another traitor.
北面之敌
Enemies to the north.
奈德·史塔克的私生子已经被拥作北境之王
Ned Stark's bastard has been named King in the North
杀了我儿子的那个臭婊子珊莎也与他为伍
and that murdering whore Sansa stands beside him.
四面都是敌人 我们被背叛者们团团包围着
Enemies everywhere. We're surrounded by traitors.
如今你是兰尼斯特军队的统领
You're in command of the Lannister army now.
-你准备如何开始？-可是凛冬已至
- How do we proceed? - Winter is here.
粮草不济的情况下 我们不可能打赢
We can't win a war if we can't feed our men and our horses.
提利尔家族有粮食 有牲畜
The Tyrells have the grain, the Tyrells have the livestock.
那么提利尔家族
Will the Tyrell bannermen stand alongside
会跟多斯拉克部落和无垢者为伍吗？
a Dothraki horde and Unsullied slave soldiers?
如果他们笃定丹妮莉丝会赢的话
If they think Daenerys will win.
没人想为败者拼命
No one wants to fight on the losing side.
现在看来 我们没什么胜算
Right now, we look like the losing side.
我可是统领七大王国的女王
I'm the Queen of the Seven Kingdoms.
顶多三个了
Three kingdoms, at best.
我想 你可能并不了解我们现在的处境有多危险
I'm not sure you understand how much danger we're in.
我知道我们打的是生存之战
I understand we're in a war for survival.
我知道 败者没有活路
I understand whoever loses dies.
我知道胜者就能建立一个王朝
I understand whoever wins could launch a dynasty
并且会永存于世
that lasts a thousand years.
建了王朝给谁啊？
A dynasty for whom?
我们的孩子都已经死了
Our children are dead.
我们是兰尼斯特家族最后的成员
We're the last of us.
那就是属于我们的王朝
A dynasty for us, then.
我们还没谈谈托曼
We never talked about Tommen.
没什么好说的
There's nothing to say.
我们的宝贝儿子自我了断了
Our baby boy killed himself.
他背叛了我
He betrayed me.
他背叛了我们俩
He betrayed us both.
难道我们要浪费时间为去世的
Should we spend our days mourning the dead...
母亲 父亲 还有我们的孩子们默哀吗？
Mother, father, and all our children?
-瑟曦… -我是爱他们的 真的
- Cersei... - I loved them. I did.
但现在他们已化为灰烬 而我们还活生生地站在这里
But they're ashes now and we're still flesh and blood.
我们是兰尼斯特家族最后的成员 最后能算得上的了
We're the last Lannisters, the last ones who count.
就算是兰尼斯特家族 没有盟军也是活不下去的
Even Lannisters can't survive without allies.
我们的盟军在哪？
Where are our allies now?
你瞧瞧瓦德·佛雷和他家族发生的一切
You saw what happened to Walder Frey and his family.
我听说了
I heard.
-但我们怎能相信那种人？-我们不能
- How could we ever trust a man like that? - We couldn't.
他就是个没用的懦夫
He was a useless, old coward,
但佛雷家族拥护我们
but the Freys supported us.
他们现在全死光了
Now they're all dead.
杀他们的人不会是我们的朋友
Whoever killed them is no friend of ours.
我们需要盟友
We need allies.
更强的 更厉害的盟友
Stronger, better allies.
我们不可能独胜
We can't win this war alone.
你以为我听命于父亲四十年就没有学到点什么吗？
You think I listened to father for 40 years and learned nothing?
葛雷乔伊家族？
The Greyjoys?
你邀请葛雷乔伊家族来君临？
You invited the Greyjoys to King's Landing?
-没有邀请所有 -好吧 看起来就像是全部
- Not all of them. - Well, it looks like all of them.
我邀请的是攸伦·葛雷乔伊
I invited Euron Greyjoy,
新的铁群岛之王
the new King of the Iron Islands.
你自己说过我们需要更强更厉害的盟友
You said yourself we needed stronger, better allies.
-他们不就是么 -他们怎么能算得上是更好的盟友？
- There you are. - How are they better allies?
他们和佛雷家族有何不同？
How are they different from the Freys?
他们都违背了自己的誓言
They both broke their promises
为了自己的利益背刺了之前的盟友
and murdered their former friends as soon as it suited them.
时机恰当的话 每个人都会这么做的
So does everyone when it suits them.
和佛雷家族不同的是 他们还有船
Unlike the Freys, they have ships.
-而且他们擅长杀敌 -他们什么都不擅长
- And they're good at killing. - They're not good at anything.
我知道铁种 都是些个尖酸刻薄的小人
I know the ironborn. They're bitter, angry little people.
自己不建东西不种东西 只知道去偷东西
All they know how to do is steal things they can't build or grow themselves.
攸伦·葛雷乔伊又不是来偷东西的
Euron Greyjoy didn't come here for that.
是嘛 那他为何而来？
Oh, what did he come here for, then?
他们要一个王后
A queen.
从我被选为铁群岛首领的那一刻起
The moment I was chosen Lord of the Iron Islands,
他们就背叛了我
they turned on me.
我可是他们的亲叔叔
Their own uncle.
他们偷了我最精良的舰队 逃跑了
They stole my best ships and ran.
攸伦·葛雷乔伊
“鸦眼” 铁群岛之王
开着船横穿整个世界
Sailed them right across the world
再把舰队献给龙女王
and gave them to the Dragon Queen
这样她就能渡海 来攻打你
so she could bring her armies here to attack you.
不过 和你所遭遇的背叛相比起来 这不算什么
It's nothing compared to the treason you suffered
据我说知是被家族至亲背叛了
at the hands of a family member, from what I hear.
但 这始终困扰着我
But still, it bothers me.
杀了他们会让我好受些
Murdering them would make me feel a lot better.
而且自从背叛我的家族成员站成一派
And since it appears that all our treasonous family members
来对抗我
are fighting for the same side,
我就认为我们这些合法统治者
I thought we rightful monarchs
应该把他们都杀了
could murder them together.
劳勃·斯壮
“魔山”
不过 你并不是合法的统治者 不是吗？
You're not a rightful monarch, though, are you?
为了能自己当上统治者 你们曾经反抗过
The Greyjoys rebelled against the throne for the right to be monarchs,
不过我记得 你们被彻底击败了
but as I recall, you were soundly defeated.
说到这里
Come to mention it,
你不就是那个掀起叛乱的人吗？
weren't you the one who started that rebellion
你的舰队跑来凯岩城 把兰尼斯特舰队给烧了
by sailing to Casterly Rock and burning the Lannister fleet?
你引起了我们的注意
You certainly caught us there.
从你们的角度来讲 这个计划非常聪明
Very smart move on your part.
当然了 反正我们都去了铁群岛
Of course, we all made it to the Iron Islands anyway.
我就在那儿
I was there.
所以我记忆犹新
I remember very well.
我见到过你
I saw you.
你的传说可多了
I heard so much talk.
盖世无敌 所向披靡
The best in the world. No one can stop him.
说实话 我原先一个字都不信
I didn't believe it, to be honest.
可我不得不承认 当你破浪而来
But I must say when you rushed through the breach
手起刀落
and started cutting people down...
真是精彩
it was glorious.
你的剑法跟舞蹈一样
Like a dance.
我杀的可是你的骨肉至亲
The people I was cutting down were your own kin.
铁群岛太挤了
The place was getting crowded.
这对我来说喜闻乐见
I enjoyed watching it. I truly did.
斩杀葛雷乔伊族人也让我感到乐在其中
And I enjoyed killing Greyjoys.
我也一样
A good thing for me.
如果不是你把我们击败 我就不会被流放海外
If you hadn't crushed us, I wouldn't have gone into exile.
如果我不曾被流放
If I hadn't done that,
我就不会成为十四大洋最有名的舰长
I wouldn't be the greatest captain on the 14 seas.
难道不是最卑微的？
If not the most humble.
您可不卑微
You're not humble.
您是女王 统御四方
You're the queen of a great nation.
铁群岛于您 何足挂齿
You don't care about the Iron Islands.
不过是怪石兀立 遍地鸟粪之地
They're nothing but rocks and bird shit and...
全是刁民恶棍
And a lot of very unattractive people.
而铁舰队于您
The Iron Fleet, on the other hand,
则有另一重意义
that's something else entirely.
那可是维斯特洛最庞大的舰队
It's the greatest armada Westeros has ever seen.
有了它 便有了大海
With the Iron Fleet, you own the seas.
您可攻破东面的来犯之敌
You can defeat the invaders of the east
亦可粉碎北境南疆的僭越之徒
and the pretenders of the north and south.
那么 你想要什么？
What do you want in return?
自我年幼时起
Ever since I was a little boy,
便想长大迎娶
I wanted to grow up and marry
世上最美貌的女子
the most beautiful woman in the world.
所以 我来了
So here I am,
携带千艘长船
with a thousand ships
还有两只好手
and two good hands.
我拒绝你的求婚
I decline your proposal.
为什么？
Why?
你不值得信任
You're not trustworthy.
你背弃过盟友
You've broken promises to allies before
时机一到便将他们斩尽杀绝
and murdered them at the nearest opportunity.
你谋害兄长
You murdered your own brother.
您不妨一试 那感觉妙不可言
You should try it. Feels wonderful.
我不指望您与我推心置腹
I don't expect you to trust me outright.
您只需要确信我的一片赤诚之心
You need proof of my honest intentions.
以我的经验
In my experience,
要赢得佳人芳心 送礼最为稳妥
the surest way to a woman's heart is with a gift.
礼物要无价之宝
A priceless gift.
我重返君临城之时
I won't return to King's Landing
必会为您带来这份无价之礼
until I have that for you.
山姆威尔·塔利
学城学徒
啊 韦兰学士
Ah, Maester Weyland.
酒鬼的肝 真是屡见不鲜
A drinker's liver if ever I saw one.
称下重量
Weigh that.
片刻欢愉就能征服人性
The triumph of transitory pleasures.
这真是给人的诅咒
Mankind's curse.
首学士 我想问……
Archmaester, I was wondering...
多重？
What's the weight?
呃 147
Um, 147.
我想问 您是否考虑过我的请求
I was wondering if you had considered my proposition.
我不记得你提过请求
I don't remember your proposition.
我曾问您 鉴于我在北境所见
I asked you if, in light of what I've seen in the North,
我是否可以获准进入图书馆禁区
if I could have access to the restricted area of the library.
禁区是学士专属
That area is reserved for maesters.
-你是学士吗？-不是
- Are you a maester? - No.
这么看来你的请求不太合理啊
Not a very strong proposition, is it?
博士 请您恕我直言
Archmaester, with respect,
我亲眼见过他们……
I've seen them...
尸鬼大军
The Army of the Dead.
还有异鬼
The white walkers.
我来到这里 就是为了学会击败他们的方法
I was sent here to learn how to defeat them,
然而学城的每一个人
but everyone in the Citadel,
那些愿意听我说的人
those who will even talk to me,
他们总是怀疑异鬼是否真实存在
they all doubt the walkers ever existed in the first place.
学城的每一个人都会质疑万物
Everyone in the Citadel doubts everything.
这是他们的任务
It's their job.
然而长夜传说并非空穴来风
But the tales of the Long Night can't be pure fabrication.
许多不相关的文献都有过相似记载
Too many similarities from unconnected sources.
禁区的文献？
Sources in the restricted area?
正是
The very same.
最简单的解释就是
And the simplest explanation
对于你念念不忘的异鬼
for your grating obsession with the white walkers
你说的都是事实
is that you're telling the truth
你说你看到了 而你确实真的看到了
and that you saw what you say you saw.
所以 您相信我
So, you believe me.
我相信
I do.
你到底有没有称完那颗心脏？
You'll finish weighing that heart?
您是孪河城以南唯一相信我的人
That makes you the only person south of the Twins who does.
我们可不像孪河城以南的普罗大众
We're not like the people south of the Twins.
也不像孪河城以北的人们
And we're not like the people north of the Twins.
学城的人们为着各自的使命过着不同的生活
In the Citadel, we lead different lives for different reasons.
我们记录这个世界的记忆 山姆威尔·塔利
We are this world's memory, Samwell Tarly.
没有我们 人们与家犬何异
Without us, men would be little better than dogs.
脑子里只记得上一顿吃的东西
Don't remember any meal but the last,
眼里只看得见身边的事物
can't see forward to any but the next.
而我们一旦外出 紧闭房门
And every time you leave the house and shut the door,
他们就哀嚎不已 以为我们再也不回来了
they howl like you're gone forever.
当劳勃的叛乱爆发时
When Robert's Rebellion was raging,
人们以为末日来临
people thought the end was near.
坦格利安王朝的末日来了 “我们该如何存活？”
The end of the Targaryen dynasty. "How will we survive?"
当伊耿·坦格利安向西虎视眈眈
When Aegon Targaryen turned his eye westward
策龙踏平黑水河
and flew his dragons to Blackwater Rush...
“末日来临！我们该如何存活？”
"The end is near! How will we survive?"
而在数千年以前 长夜降临之时
And thousands of years before that, during the Long Night,
他们认为那时便是末日 也是一个道理
we can forgive them for thinking it truly was the end.
然而一切未曾终结 那些时刻都不曾是末日
But it wasn't. None of it was.
绝境长城 岿然不动
The Wall has stood through it all.
而每个冬天 都会过去
And every winter that ever came has ended.
好孩子 把这收拾干净了
Be a good lad. Clean this up.
不行
Nope.
塔斯的布蕾妮
“美人”
波德瑞克·派恩
侍从
不行
Nope.
你真幸运
You're a lucky man.
我听说她单挑打赢了猎狗
I've heard she beat the Hound in single combat.
培提尔·贝里席
“小指头” 峡谷守护者
这女人真是让人印象深刻
She's a very impressive woman.
你想要什么 贝里席大人
What do you want, Lord Baelish?
我想要你开心
I want you to be happy.
我想要你安全
I want you to be safe.
我很安全
I am safe.
我在家 和朋友们在一起
I'm at home, surrounded by friends.
布蕾妮保护我不受任何人伤害
I have Brienne to protect me from anyone who would harm me.
那你开心吗？
What about happy?
你为什么不开心
Why aren't you happy?
你想要什么你现在没有的东西？
What do you want that you do not have?
现在 我想要和平安宁
At the moment, peace and quiet.
不用再说了贝里席大人
No need to seize the last word, Lord Baelish.
我就假装你要说的这句话很聪明
I'll assume it was something clever.
布蕾妮小姐
My lady.
失陪了 小姐
为什么他还在这儿
Why is he still here?
我们需要他的人手
We need his men.
没有谷地 拉姆斯·波顿还会占据着临冬城
Without the Vale, Ramsay Bolton would still hold this castle.
小指头救了我们
Littlefinger saved us.
他想要些什么
He wants something.
我很清楚他想要什么
I know exactly what he wants.
他骑马穿过街道
♪ He rode through the streets of the city ♪
冲下伊耿的高丘
♪ Down from his hill on high ♪
速度比任何风或任何脚步都快
♪ O'er the winds and the steps and the cobbles ♪
他终于冲到她身边
♪ He rode to a woman's sigh ♪
因为她是他私藏的宝藏
♪ For she was his secret treasure ♪
也是他的耻辱和荣耀
♪ She was his shame and his bliss ♪
冰冷的锁链也不算什么
♪ And a chain and a keep are nothing ♪
比起她甜蜜的吻
♪ Compared to a woman's kiss ♪
金手触摸冰冰凉啊
♪ For hands of gold are always cold ♪
而姑娘小掌热乎乎
♪ But a woman's hands are warm ♪
金手触摸冰冰凉啊
♪ For hands of gold are always cold ♪
而姑娘小掌…
♪ But a woman's hands are... ♪
这歌很好听
That's a pretty song.
我以前从没听过
I've never heard it before.
这是首新歌
It's a new one.
饿吗？我们有兔肉
Are you hungry? We've got some rabbit.
我不想偷你们的食物
I don't want to steal your food.
你不是偷 我们主动给你
You're not stealing, we're offering.
来吧 今晚会很冷的
Come on, it's gonna be a cold night.
你要去南边？
You heading south?
去君临
King's Landing.
可怜姑娘
Poor girl.
没那么差 是吧？
Not so bad, is it?
看你口味了 我觉得
Depends on your taste, I guess.
如果你喜欢街上到处是屎和猪血 那你就去对地方了
If you like your streets covered in shit and pig's blood, it's the town for you.
我这辈子一直都想看红堡
All my life, I wanted to see the Red Keep,
贝勒大教堂 龙穴
the Sept of Baelor, the Dragonpit.
当我终于到了
Then when I finally make it,
他们却把我拦在红堡一里之外
they wouldn't let me within a mile of the Red Keep,
贝勒大教堂已经被炸毁了
the Sept of Baelor's blown to hell,
龙穴则成了废墟
and the Dragonpit is a damn ruin.
住那儿的人
The people who live there,
他们会活剥了你 说不定还能卖两个铜板
they'd skin you alive if they could make two coppers off your hide.
全世界最烂的地方
Worst place in the world.
你们在河间地干什么？
What are you doing in the Riverlands?
孪河城的佛雷家遇到了些麻烦
There's been some trouble with the Freys up at the Twins,
我们是过来维护治安的
so we're part of the army that's been sent to keep the peace.
你来吧 客人优先
Here you go. Guests first.
不 我不能吃 否则你们就不够吃了
Oh, no, I couldn't. You don't have enough.
我妈总告诉我对陌生人要友好
My mother always told me to be kind to strangers.
陌生人也会对你友好
Strangers will be kind to you.
你们离家这么远
You're a long way from home.
我猜你们的经历肯定都很刺激
I'm sure you've had some adventures, though.
是 多到数不过来
Yeah, endless adventures.
他们会在歌谣里传唱我们一千年
They'll be singing about us for a thousand years.
事实上我们离家时 迫不及待远走高飞
The truth is when we left home, we couldn't wait to get away.
但现在我们离开了一段时间 又渴望回家
But now we've been gone a while, we can't wait to get home.
我就想起我爸一个人乘船出去
I just think about my dad out there on his boat all alone.
我就应该和他在一起
I ought to be out there with him.
我妻子刚生下我们第一个孩子
My wife just had our first baby.
-男孩还是女孩？-啊 谁知道啊
- Boy or girl?- Oh, who knows?
你以为士兵能收到家里的渡鸦来信吗？
You think soldiers get ravens with news from home?
-我希望是女孩-为什么？
- I hope it's a girl.- Why?
爹要是老了 女孩可以照顾爹
Girls take care of their papas when their papas grow old.
男孩只能上战场 为别人作战
Boys just go off to fight in someone else's wars.
你这岁数 能喝酒吗？
Are you old enough to drink?
这是黑莓酒
It's blackberry wine.
我自己酿的
I made it myself.
真不错
It's really good.
所以 为什么这么个漂亮姑娘要自己去君临？
So, why is a nice girl on her own heading to King's Landing?
我要去杀女王
I'm going to kill the queen.
今晚不该出门啊
Bad night to be outdoors.
能察觉到这点你的法力还真是强大
You've got real powerful magic to figure that out.
光之王和你说悄悄话了吗？
Did the Lord of Light whisper that in your ear?
贝里·唐德利恩
“闪电大王”
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗”
密尔的索罗斯
红袍僧
“外面下雪了 索罗斯 起风了
"It's snowing, Thoros. It's windy.
今晚会很冷”
It's gonna be a cold night."
你真是头坏脾气的熊啊 是不是 克里冈？
You're a grouchy old bear, aren't you, Clegane?
来点朗姆酒吗？
You want some rum?
不爱喝那垃圾玩意儿 太甜
Don't like that shit. It's too sweet.
你怎么总这么阴沉？
Why are you always in such a foul mood?
因为经历
Experience.
这儿看起来像是个过夜的好去处
This seems like a good place to spend the night.
那里的人不想让我们待在这里
These people don't want us here.
我看这里已经废弃了 没有牲畜
Seems deserted to me. No livestock.
烟囱里不冒烟
No smoke coming from the chimney.
我不喜欢这里的样子
I don't like the look of it.
你块头这么大 胆子倒是挺小
For a big, hard man, you scare easy.
我来告诉你什么吓不住我
I'll tell you what doesn't scare me...
你这种秃头混蛋
Bald cocksuckers like you.
你以为你头上梳个髻就能唬住别人了吗？
You think you're fooling anyone with that top knot?
秃头龟孙
Bald cunt.
来吧
Come on.
也许他们藏了些麦酒
Maybe they've got some ale hidden away.
不会的
They don't.
看看有没有粮仓
See if there's a larder.
他们总会留点什么
They always leave something behind.
你觉得他们遭遇了什么？
How do you think it ended for them?
死亡
With death.
女儿死在了父亲的怀里
Girl died in her father's arms.
他们浑身是血 脚下还有一把刀
Both of them covered in blood and a knife at their feet.
我觉着眼见着快要饿死
I'd say they were starving.
父亲不愿让女儿受苦
And rather than let his little girl suffer,
便了结了两人的生命
he ended it for both of them.
如今也无所谓了
Doesn't matter now.
是啊 无所谓了
No, doesn't matter now.
我认识你很久了 唐德利恩
I've known you a long time, Dondarrion.
是啊
Aye.
我记得第一次遇见你是在那次比武大会…
I think the first time we met was at that tournament...
我一直以为你是个榆木脑袋
And I always thought you were dull as dirt.
可你还不赖
You're not bad.
我不讨厌你
I don't hate you.
我不喜欢你 不过你也不赖
Don't like you,but you're not bad.
谢了 克里冈
Thank you, Clegane.
这些话很暖心
That warms the heart.
但是你没什么特别之处
But there's nothing special about you.
这话倒不假
You're right about that.
那为什么光之王一直让你复活？
So why does the Lord of Light keep bringing you back?
我见过比你更好的人
I've met better men than you,
他们被吊死在横梁上 或者被斩首
and they've been hanged from crossbeams, or beheaded,
或者就是暴尸荒野
or just shat themselves to death in a field somewhere.
他们中没一个还能复活
None of them came back.
所以 为什么你能？
So, why you?
你觉得我不会扪心自问吗？
You think I don't ask myself that?
每时每刻？
Every hour of every day?
为什么我还在这？
Why am I here?
我应该做什么？
What am I supposed to do?
主看中了我的什么？
What does the Lord see in me?
所以呢？
And?
我不知道
I don't know.
我不理解我们的主
I don't understand our Lord.
是你的主
Your Lord.
我不知道他想从我这里得到什么
I don't know what he wants from me.
我只知道他想让我活下去
I only know that he wants me alive.
如果他这么全能 为什么他不直接告诉你他想要什么？
If he's so all-powerful, why doesn't he just tell you what the fuck he wants?
克里冈
Clegane.
到这边来
Come over here.
别担心 火又不会咬人
Don't worry.The fire won't bite.
我想给你看些东西
I want to show you something.
我跟一群拜火者搭伙真是他妈的走运
It's my fucking luck I end up with a band of fire worshippers.
是啊
Aye.
几乎可以说是天降正义
Almost seems like divine justice.
哪里有什么天降正义 你个蠢蛋
There's no divine justice,you dumb cunt.
有的话 你早死了……
If there was, you'd be dead...
而那个女孩会活下来
and that girl would be alive.
- 你想干什么？ - 瞧这火焰
- What do you want? - Look into the flames.
我不想看这傻逼火焰
I don't want to look in the damn flames.
你曾把他砍到 之后亲眼见到我把他起死回生
You saw me bring him back from the dead after you cut him down.
你不想知道我的法力是怎么来的吗？
Don't you want to know what gave me the power?
我一直在问 可没人愿意告诉我
I keep asking and no one wants to tell me.
我们没法告诉你
We can't tell you.
只有火焰能告诉你
Only the fire can tell you.
你看到了什么？
What do you see?
柴在烧
Logs burning.
继续看
Keep looking.
看到了什么？
What do you see?
冰
Ice.
一座冰墙
A wall of ice.
是绝境长城
The Wall.
还有什么？
What else?
绝境长城与海交汇的地方
It's where the Wall meets the sea.
有一座城堡
There's a castle there.
有一座山
There's a mountain.
看起来像个箭头
Looks like an arrowhead.
亡者大军正在行军通过
The dead are marching past.
成千上万的亡者
Thousands of them.
克里冈 你现在相信我了吗？
Do you believe me now, Clegane?
你相信我们不是随随便便就跑到这里来了吧？
Do you believe we're here for a reason?
克里冈 你这是干什么呢？
What the hell are you doing, Clegane?
埋葬死者
Burying the dead.
认识？
You knew these people.
不怎么认识
Not really.
我们祈求天父仁慈的审判
We ask the Father to judge us with mercy.
我们祈求圣母……
We ask the Mother to...
操 后面我忘了
Fuck it, I don't remember the rest.
我很遗憾你们死了
I'm sorry you're dead.
你们本该有更好的结局
You deserved better.
两个人都是
Both of you.
嘿
Hey.
妈妈
Mom.
吉莉
野人
山姆 你真的该睡觉了
You should really sleep, Sam.
尸鬼可不会
The dead don't.
“长夜的传说”
"Legends of the Long Night."
坦格利安家族用龙晶来装饰他们的武器
The Targaryens used dragonglass to decorate their weapons
却不知道先民用它来干什么
without even knowing what the First Men used it for.
这是什么？
What is it?
这是龙石岛的地图
It's a map of Dragonstone.
坦格利安家族入侵维斯特洛时
The Targaryens built their first stronghold there
在这里建造了他们的第一个要塞
when they invaded Westeros.
那是龙晶吗？
That's dragonglass?
一整座山的龙晶
A mountain of it.
埋藏在地下
Beneath the ground.
史坦尼斯告诉过我 可我没想到……
Stannis told me,but I didn't think...
这很重要 琼恩得知道这个消息
This is important.Jon needs to know.
她来了吗？
Has she come yet?
谁？
Who?
龙女王
The Dragon Queen.
”风暴降生“丹妮莉丝
Daenerys Stormborn.
还没听到消息
Haven't heard anything.
乔拉·莫尔蒙
“大熊”
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
“风暴降生” 龙之母
提利昂·兰尼斯特
女王之手
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛”
弥桑黛
灰虫子
我们开始吧？
Shall we begin?